Mike North: 类型参数也可以有约束。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Type parameters
can also have constraints.
因此，当您开始使用类型参数时，您将
So, as you'll start using type parameters,
you'll
如果没有这样的约束，这就是约束部分。
see that if you don't have a constraint
like this, this is the constraint part.
也就是说 t 必须扩展，必须可赋值到，这里的这个类型。
This is saying T must extend,
must be assignable to, this type here.
我向您解释约束的最好方法是移除它
The best way I can explain
constraints to you is to remove this
来揭示添加它的动机。
to reveal the motivation for adding it.
这就对了。
And there you go.
因此，我们得到了一个类型错误，因为我们正在尝试
So, we're getting a type
error because we're trying
将类型 t 的数组转换为类型 t 的字典。
to transform an array of type
T to a dictionary of type T.
我们首先创建一个空字典，遍历数组,
And we begin by creating an empty
dictionary, we iterate over the array,
我们试着把每个值都放进字典里，但结果不行
we try to place each value into
the dictionary, but it turns out we can't
从数组的每个成员访问这个属性 ID。
access this property ID off
of each member of our array.
原因是我们还没有宣布
And the reason is we have
not declared that there is
一个 t 必须满足的最低要求，因此,
a minimum requirement that T must meet,
and as a result,
对于函数内 t 类型的值，我们能做的很少。
there's very little that we can do with
values of type T inside the function.
在传递给函数的内容方面，它确实很灵活，但是
It's really flexible in terms of what
can be passed into the function, but
你只能做你明确要求的事情。
you can only do the things that
you've explicitly asked for.
如果我们需要访问 ID，我们必须声明 t 必须是一个对象和
If we need to access ID,
we must state that T must be an object and
它必须有一个名为 ID 的属性，这就是我们要做的。
it must have a property called ID,
and this is how we would do it.
我们接受一个 t 型，至少是
We accept a type T, that is at least
具有值为字符串的属性 ID 的对象。
an object with a property
ID whose value is a string.
现在，这是一根绳子。
And now, this would be a string.
这相当于做这样的事情,
So, this is the equivalent of
doing something like this,
我们可以尝试移除这个然后说,
that we could try to remove this and
just say,
我用一个数组，Mike North: Of
I'm taking an array,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Of
看起来像这样的物体。
objects that look like this.
我们可以尝试改变这种状况。
And we could try to change this.
迈克 · 诺斯: 对，我们可以把这里的 t 替换掉。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Right, instead of T there,
we can replace the T here.
我们会遇到另一个问题。
We're gonna run into another problem.
所以，我基本上把这些归结为我的最低要求。
So, I've basically boiled this
down to my minimum requirements.
我说过把这个数组转换成一个字典，但是
I've said transform this
array to a dictionary, but
没有类型参数了。
there's no type parameter any more.
这就是我们将遇到的问题。
Here's the problem we'll run into.
第一，我们在传入任何属性时都会得到错误
Number one, we're getting errors for
passing in any properties
不仅仅是拥有一个 ID，其值是一个字符串。
that are more than simply having
an ID who's value is a string.
另一个问题是，迈克 · 诺斯: 当我们尝试访问
The other problem we'll get is,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: When we try to access
我们大大简化了这种类型，不是吗？
things off of it, we've greatly
simplified this type in a bad way, right?
我们已经失去了所有这些额外的东西。
We've lost any of this extra
stuff that was passed in.
我们想要的是能够传入任何 ID 为字符串的东西,
What we want is to be able to pass in
anything that has an ID that's a string,
把它从数组重新编排成字典。
and to get out a rearrangement of
this from an array to a dictionary.
但我们并没有失去任何忠诚,
But we haven't lost any
fidelity in the types,
我们仍然可以拿到我们放进去的所有东西。
we still have access to
everything we put in.
这就是我们要说的，好吧，不管你给我什么
And that's where we're gonna say,
all right whatever you give me
一个 t 类型的数组，我会给你一个 t 类型的字典，对吗？
an array of type T, I'm gonna give you
a dictionary of type T out, right?
你还是会继续研究你所经历的一切,
You'll still be working
with whatever you pass in,
你还是可以用字典的形式找回来。
you'll still get it back
in dictionary form.
我不会把它简化为只有 ID 的对象,
I'm not gonna reduce it down
to just objects that have ID,
你会得到你给我的东西。
you'll have it as you gave it to me.
然后是类型约束，我们已经讨论过了。
And then the type constraint,
we already went over.
这相当于说，看，我不只是要采取，这是一种方式
This is the equivalent of saying, look,
I'm not just gonna take, it's a way of
在函数中说明您使用这种类型的需求。
stating your requirements for working
with this type within the function.
迈克 · 诺斯: 为什么一切都不快乐？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And
why isn't everything happy?
我忘了最后一件事。
I forgot one last thing.
现在我们没事了。
Now we're good.
迈克 · 诺斯: 让我们来回顾一下，通过把这个抽象化，通过添加
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So just to recap,
by making this abstract, by adding
这个通用的概念，迈克诺斯: 我们
this idea of a generic,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: We
麦克 · 诺斯: 保留细节
can,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Retain the detail of
我们传入的对象，即使这个函数正在做功,
the object we passed in even though
this function that was doing the work,
它对这些额外的属性一无所知。
it knows nothing about these extra
properties that might be there.
但是因为它给了我们一个空白，我们可以填补，从外面我们可以说,
But because it's given us a blank that we
can fill in, from the outside we can say,
为了调用这个函数,
for the purposes of invoking
this function right now,
我给你一个巨大的对象，在一个 ID 中有很多属性
I'm giving you huge objects with
lots of properties in an ID, and
你会找回同样的类型，你将不必处理排序最低
you'll get those same types back, you
won't have to deal with sort of the lowest
共同点，因为这让你处于一种
common denominator, cuz that puts you
in a position where you sort of have
想办法再次扩展你的类型，让它更有用。
to like figure out a way to widen your
types again to make this more useful.
像函数参数一样,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Like function arguments,
类型参数与作用域关联。
type parameters
are associated with a scope.
这里我们有一个函数返回一个函数，开始元组，完成元组,
So here we have a function that returns
a function, start tuple, finish tuple,
对吧？
right?
我们使用的技术
And we're using a technique that
凯尔辛普森在他的前端大师课程的函数光编程。
Kyle Simpson in his Frontend Masters
course on functional light programming.
他称之为零点编程，因为我们返回一个函数
He calls this zero point programming
because we're returning a function and
然后调用它立即返回的函数。
then invoking the function
that it returns immediately.
所以我们传入一个参数一个字符串数组,
So we pass in one argument,
an array of strings,
第二个参数，一个数字，我们得到的元组类型是。
a second argument, a number, and
the type of the tuple we get out is this.
就像 a 和 b 一样，对吧？
So just like A and B, right?
这些值是常规函数参数,
The values,
those are regular function parameters,
在这里我们可以同时访问 a 和 b。
in here we can access both A and B.
因为泛型就像函数一样,
And because of this analogy where
generics are like functions,
我们也可以访问 u 和 t。
we can also access U and T.
现在在94号线，我们可以进入 b 区吗？
Now out here on line 94,
could we access B?
迈克 · 诺斯: 没有，而且我们也不能访问你,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: No, and
we can't access U either,
它们以同样的方式与瞄准镜联系在一起。
they are associated with
scopes in the same way.
这与我们所拥有的
And this fits similarly to having
类中的类型参数，然后是该类中的方法，对吗？
a type parameter on a class and
then on a method within that class, right?
外部和内部范围。
Outer and inner scope.
你可以有一个类，一个类中的方法，一个返回的函数,
You could have a class, a method within
the class, a function that that returns,
它的工作正如你所期望的，因为我发现这是一个非常有效的类比。
it works just as you'd expect cuz I've
found this to be a very effective analogy.